<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://letscooktime.com/Blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://letscooktime.com/Blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-02-11T16:23:30-05:00</updated><id>https://letscooktime.com/Blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CookTime Blog</title><subtitle>CookTime Blog</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Refactoring to React</title><link href="https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2023/01/16/reimplement-react.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Refactoring to React" /><published>2023-01-16T19:36:58-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-16T19:36:58-05:00</updated><id>https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2023/01/16/reimplement-react</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2023/01/16/reimplement-react.html"><![CDATA[<p>Since the beginning, CookTime was mainly an ASP.NET Razor page application with a small amount of React, mainly for the very interactive recipe edit page.
This was fine for a while, but I’ve been using React more at work and I’ve decided that Razor pages, while good, lack the development maturity, mindshare, and interactivity of React. 
I’ve resolved to reimplement the CookTime UI as a React single page application (SPA) with these goals:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Make frontend development interactive with Hot Module Reload (HMR)</li>
  <li>Create re-useable and testable frontend components</li>
  <li>Use proper DTOs instead of marshalling database objects between server and client (exploring using GraphQL for this?).</li>
</ol>

<p>This post will be a development diary of all the changes necessary to accomplish this goal.
Let’s dive in!</p>

<h1 id="day-1-getting-something-running">Day 1: Getting something running</h1>
<p>I’m going to use <a href="https://create-react-app.dev">create-react-app</a> to scaffold the initial state of the client app.
I did this by running <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">npx create-react-app client-app --template typescript</code> at the root of the repo, which gets a React SPA set up in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">client-app</code> directory.</p>

<p>Next I need to integrate the frontend development server with the backend server.
This is required only for <em>development</em> though setting it up is a little tedious and confusing so I’ll try my best to explain it to future me.
In production, the ASP.NET server would be serving the SPA as static pre-compiled HTML, JS, and CSS.
This is great because clients can cache resources to make page loads faster and server resources are mostly spent on serving REST calls instead of rendering HTML for the client.
However this means that if we want HMR, the ASP.NET server has to open and maintain a connection to browser clients and push changes to files as they are made.
This used to be the case with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Microsoft.AspNetCore.SpaServices.Extensions</code> and to configure it you would have to add startup code like this:</p>

<div class="language-csharp highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="n">app</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">Map</span><span class="p">(</span>
    <span class="s">"/js"</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">ctx</span> <span class="p">=&gt;</span>
    <span class="p">{</span>
        <span class="n">ctx</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">UseSpa</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">spa</span> <span class="p">=&gt;</span>
        <span class="p">{</span>
            <span class="n">spa</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">UseProxyToSpaDevelopmentServer</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">"http://localhost:8080/js"</span><span class="p">);</span>
        <span class="p">});</span>
    <span class="p">});</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This tells ASP.NET that any call to a path starting with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/js</code> should be proxied to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">http://localhost:8080/js</code> where, hopefully, a second server is running listing for filesystem events to deliver the nice HMR experience.
In this case, ASP.NET is the <em>first</em> process that receives calls and decides to handle them or proxy them to another process.</p>

<p>The ASP.NET team decided they <a href="https://github.com/dotnet/AspNetCore.Docs/issues/17902">don’t want to maintain this anymore</a> citing “simplicity” arguments so we have to now invert which process handles the request first:</p>
<ol>
  <li><em>Before</em>:  ASP.NET sees the request first, if it matches a specific path (like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/js</code>) the request is proxied to the React development server.</li>
  <li><em>After</em>: The React deveopment server sees the request first, if it matches a specific path (like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/api</code>) the request is proxied to the ASP.NET development server.</li>
</ol>

<p>Same result? Yes. Better? Probably not. Does it make the web development world harder by deprecating a working solution? Yes!</p>

<p>So we replace <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Microsoft.AspNetCore.SpaServices.Extensions</code> with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Microsoft.AspNetCore.SpaProxy</code> and modify our <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">csproj</code> file to tell it how to start the development server.
The full documentation for the new NuGet is <a href="https://github.com/dotnet/AspNetCore.Docs/issues/26373">here</a> and that page does a better job than me.</p>

<p>With all that done, the standard <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">create-react-app</code> page loads with the spinning Rutherfordian atom.</p>

<p>Success!
<img src="assets/react-day1.png" alt="Create react app template" /></p>

<h1 id="day-2-authentication-and-authorization">Day 2: Authentication and Authorization</h1>

<p>Before we get to the fun parts of re-writing the Razor pages as React components, we have to deal with the un-fun features of signing in and authorizing users.
Addressing this led me down a rabbit-hole of authentication acronymns and open-ended questioning whether or not you should be able to use your Google account to sign in.
In the end, I decided that CookTime will</p>
<ol>
  <li><em>Continue</em> to be its own authentication and authorization provider.</li>
  <li><em>Continue</em> to use ASP.NET Identity cookies to identify users.</li>
</ol>

<p>The <em>alternative</em> of course would have been to</p>
<ol>
  <li>Delegate to an authentication provider (like Google, Facebook, Apple, Microsoft, etc…) and implement the correct <a href="https://openid.net/connect/">OIDC</a> flow</li>
  <li>Configure <em>each</em> authentication provider and map claims appropriately so CookTime doesn’t care who provided the JWT.</li>
</ol>

<p>I simply do not have the patience or desire to setup OAuth authentication for CookTime and if this costs us users then so be it.
The whole process is mind-meltingly boring.</p>

<p>Having decided that, I need to reimplement the Identity flows using React components instead of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">forms</code> for</p>
<ol>
  <li>Registration</li>
  <li>Sign in</li>
  <li>Sign out</li>
  <li>Password reset</li>
  <li>Email verification</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="hoes-does-aspnet-authentication-actually-work">Hoes does ASP.NET authentication actually work?</h2>
<p>If you use <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Cookies">cookie</a> authentication, the signin process just involves the server setting a cookie in a response.
<img src="assets/react-day2-2.png" alt="Cookie signin evidence" /></p>

<p>Here’s what happened:</p>
<ol>
  <li>The client POSTs a signin form with the username and password</li>
  <li>The server responds with an OK <em>and</em> the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">.AspNetCore.Identity.Application</code> cookie.</li>
  <li>The browser stores the cookie and sends it to the server in all subsequent requests in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Cookie</code> header.</li>
</ol>

<p>So how does the server authenticate the user and set the cookie? Something like this:</p>
<div class="language-csharp highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>    <span class="p">[</span><span class="nf">HttpPost</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">"signin"</span><span class="p">)]</span>
    <span class="k">public</span> <span class="k">async</span> <span class="n">Task</span><span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">IActionResult</span><span class="p">&gt;</span> <span class="nf">SignIn</span><span class="p">(</span>
        <span class="p">[</span><span class="n">FromForm</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="n">SignIn</span> <span class="n">signinRequest</span><span class="p">)</span>
    <span class="p">{</span>
        <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">logger</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">LogInformation</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">"Model state is valid, attempting login"</span><span class="p">);</span>
        <span class="kt">var</span> <span class="n">user</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="n">signinRequest</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">UserNameOrEmail</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">Contains</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="sc">'@'</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">?</span>
            <span class="k">await</span> <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">userManager</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">FindUserByEmail</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">signinRequest</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">UserNameOrEmail</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">:</span>
            <span class="k">await</span> <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">userManager</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">FindUserByUserName</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">signinRequest</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">UserNameOrEmail</span><span class="p">);</span>
        <span class="c1">// This is the line that sets the cookie in the response!!!</span>
        <span class="kt">var</span> <span class="n">result</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="k">await</span> <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">signInManager</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">SignInWithUserName</span><span class="p">(</span>
            <span class="n">userName</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">user</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">UserName</span><span class="p">,</span>
            <span class="n">password</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">signinRequest</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">Password</span><span class="p">,</span>
            <span class="n">isPersistent</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">signinRequest</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">RememberMe</span><span class="p">,</span>
            <span class="n">lockoutOnFailure</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="k">true</span><span class="p">);</span>

        <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="n">result</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">Succeeded</span><span class="p">)</span>
        <span class="p">{</span>
            <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">logger</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">LogInformation</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">"User {Email} logged in"</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">signinRequest</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">Email</span><span class="p">);</span>

            <span class="k">return</span> <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">Ok</span><span class="p">();</span>
        <span class="p">}</span>
        <span class="k">else</span>
        <span class="p">{</span>
            <span class="k">return</span> <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">BadRequest</span><span class="p">();</span>
        <span class="p">}</span>
    <span class="p">}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>An interesting feature of this particular cookie is that it has the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">HttpOnly</code> flag set, which means that JavaScript code cannot access this cookie. Even if the client side code could access the cookie, it is encrypted by the server and it wouldn’t be feasible to decrypt it without leaking keys. Without access to a decrypted cookie, our client-side code does not have any actual information about the user. We don’t know their name, what roles they have, any other claims they may have, among others.</p>

<p>To solve this, we need an <em>authenticated</em> request to a route like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/profile</code> that basically exchanges a valid authentication cookie with a JWT-like object that contains important claims like the username, roles, claims, etc… So that’s what we will do.</p>

<h2 id="registration">Registration</h2>
<p>The registration form is “simple” (Ha! Nothing with authentication is simple!).
A user providers the following information (taken from the current sign up form).</p>

<p><img src="assets/react-day2-1.png" alt="Alt text" /></p>

<p>Then in the backend, we take this and check to see if a user with the same <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">username</code> <em>or</em> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">email</code> has previously been registered.
Assuming not, we try to create the user and if their password passes the complexity checks then they get a database entry in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">AspNetUsers</code> table.
We also fire off an email to the email provided to validate that this is a real email!
It should be simple enough to:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Make a React form that accepts these 4 inputs</li>
  <li>POST the information to the server</li>
  <li>Create the user if needed</li>
</ol>

<p>… A few days later …
Indeed I did that and spent a few days in the refactoring jungles so now I will summarize some of the largest changes:</p>

<h1 id="introducing-react-router">Introducing react-router</h1>
<p>Now that we have a SPA, we have to be able to navigate between pages.
The most popular library for React to do this seems to be Remix’s <a href="https://reactrouter.com/en/main">react-router</a> so I’ve chosen to use it.
The library works like this:</p>
<ol>
  <li>You define a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">router</code> object that maps URLs to React component. Previously we relied on Razor page file organization conventions to match URL to Razor pages but now this is done explicitly by the router configuration.</li>
  <li>For each route you want to match, you define a React component that gets rendered at that route. These are the site “pages” different from reusable components.</li>
  <li>Replace all <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">href</code>s with a combination of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">To</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Link</code> elements from <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">react-router</code>. Normally, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">href</code>s make the browser navigate which is <em>verboten</em> for react-router. If you navigate, you are no longer a single-page application!</li>
</ol>

<p>Having understood react-router, the challenge here was actually rewriting every Razor page as a React page.
The UI side of this was really easy, the problem was that we were running a lot of Entity Framework queries in the backend that were never exposed as REST APIs.
For most of the pages I had to do something like this:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Write the react components</li>
  <li>Expose a REST call equivalent to the DB query we were previously performing to render the Razor page</li>
  <li>Make the frontend call the query.</li>
</ol>

<p>Simple work but it was very laborious.</p>

<h1 id="todo-performance-differences">TODO performance differences?</h1>
<h2 id="render-time">Render time</h2>
<h2 id="network-load">Network load</h2>

<h2 id="references">References</h2>
<ol>
  <li>https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Cookies</li>
  <li>https://jcbaey.com/authentication-in-spa-reactjs-and-vuejs-the-right-way/?utm_source=medium&amp;utm_campaign=spa-authentication</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since the beginning, CookTime was mainly an ASP.NET Razor page application with a small amount of React, mainly for the very interactive recipe edit page. This was fine for a while, but I’ve been using React more at work and I’ve decided that Razor pages, while good, lack the development maturity, mindshare, and interactivity of React. I’ve resolved to reimplement the CookTime UI as a React single page application (SPA) with these goals:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cumulative update</title><link href="https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/05/15/cumulative-update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cumulative update" /><published>2022-05-15T00:36:58-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-15T00:36:58-04:00</updated><id>https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/05/15/cumulative-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/05/15/cumulative-update.html"><![CDATA[<p>Almost 2 weeks without a blog post, lots of things have gotten done.
Get ready!</p>

<h1 id="new-recipes">New recipes</h1>
<p>Any recipe created in the last week will be shown in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">New Recipes</code> list of the home page.
Usually these recipes are “in-development” so showing them first makes the author’s job easier.</p>

<h1 id="feature-recipes">Feature recipes</h1>
<p>For the featured recipes lists, we query our recipe database for recipes with photos, take <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">N</code> of them, and then display them on the page.
It is preferable to ask the database to randomly sort and take the top <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">N</code> recipes after sorting, otherwise we have to load all the recipes client-side, randomize, and take <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">N</code> of them.
This can take an unnacceptable amount of time if the number of recipes is large.
CookTime uses PostgreSQL as its database, Entity Framework as the ORM, and the npsql as the bridge between LINQ queries and PostgreSQL statements. 
PostgreSQL can certainl do what we want, I found a stack overflow question asking for exactly this: https://stackoverflow.com/questions/654906/linq-to-entities-random-order</p>

<p>The only missing piece was to enable an extension on the database to allow it to generate UUIDs on-demand to create random sort orders. The query-command is this:</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">CREATE EXTENSION IF NOT EXISTS "uuid-ossp";</code></p>

<p>With all that database infrastructure in place, we now show featured recipes on the home page :).</p>

<h1 id="pagination">Pagination</h1>
<p>The home page and query results are now paginated.
This should reduce the amount of scrolling needed on mobile devices to view recipes.
We observed that users get lost if the page is too long to scroll through; pages should address this issue.</p>

<h1 id="ratings-and-reviews">Ratings and Reviews</h1>
<p>If you have a CookTime account, you can now rate and review recipes.
Your ratings will be aggregated and averaged.
Over time, we will come to find which recipes are the best recipes :)</p>

<h1 id="authentication-improvements">Authentication improvements</h1>
<p>You can now use your email OR your username to sign in to CookTime.
We now also display validation errors during the sign up process.
We have simplified the password requirements, basically you need atleast 2 unique characters and a minimum length of 6 total characters.</p>

<h1 id="categories-in-the-navigation-bar">Categories in the navigation bar</h1>
<p>During user testing, we found that users wanted to know what were all of the categories of reicpes that CookTime had recipes for.
We did not have a way to view the list of categories, but now we do!
You can click on <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Categories</code> in the navigation bar and then click on a category you’re interested in to view all recieps for that category.</p>

<h1 id="ingredient-aliases">Ingredient aliases</h1>
<p>This feature is not user-facing but it did involve a big change in our backend so I’d like to describe it.</p>

<p>Early in CookTime’s development we identified a need for ingredient aliases.
For example, “milk” and “whole milk” are practically the same ingredient, so for the purposes of auto-completion and building a correct recipe database we should treat them as the same ingredient.
Initially this was <em>not</em> the case, recipes with “milk” and “whole milk” would be referencing unique ingredients and this would create several kinds of problems for us.</p>

<p>We could not associate different variants of an ingredient name with unique nutrition facts.</p>

<p>We could not properly highlight ingredient names in the recipe text if the user used one name in the ingredients list but another name in the text.
This is extremely common: for example you might say a recipe need 6 galic cloves but then in the text of the recipe you will write “peel the garlic.”
Since you did not write exactly “garlic clove”, we would not highlight the ingredient and thats not a good user experience.</p>

<p>Another problem was that we have a power user that creates recipes in portuguese so we had to associate the portuguese words for milk if we wanted nutrition facts and all the other features to work.</p>

<p>To implement aliases, we basically store a list of names for an ingredient along with a single “canonical” name.
In the case of milk, this looks like:
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Milk; Leite; Whole Milk</code>
Where <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Milk</code> is the canonical name, and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Leite</code> (milk in portugues) and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Whole Milk</code> are aliases for this ingredient.</p>

<p>The bulk of the work of this change was to hide from the user the fact that an ingredient’s name is now a semi-colon separated list of possible aliases.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Almost 2 weeks without a blog post, lots of things have gotten done. Get ready!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Favorites and mine</title><link href="https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/05/05/favorites-and-mine.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Favorites and mine" /><published>2022-05-05T00:36:58-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-05T00:36:58-04:00</updated><id>https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/05/05/favorites-and-mine</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/05/05/favorites-and-mine.html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now favorite recipes, and view just the recipes you own.</p>

<p>Favoriting is done by a clicking on a button in a recipe card.</p>

<p>You can view just your recipes by clicking on your name in the nav bar and then clicking on “My recipes”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can now favorite recipes, and view just the recipes you own.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Automatic unit conversions</title><link href="https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/05/02/automatic-conversions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Automatic unit conversions" /><published>2022-05-02T00:36:58-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-02T00:36:58-04:00</updated><id>https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/05/02/automatic-conversions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/05/02/automatic-conversions.html"><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever had a recipe measure an ingredient by mass, but you don’t have a scale? Or the opposite sitation: a recipe that measures by volume but you don’t have a measuring cup.</p>

<p>Now CookTime will automatically show you mass and volume for all ingredients. The conversion is very simple: if we know the density of the ingredient based on the USDA dataset, we will show you the opposite unit in SI unit. For example, 1 cup of milk will <em>also</em> be shown as 244g.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever had a recipe measure an ingredient by mass, but you don’t have a scale? Or the opposite sitation: a recipe that measures by volume but you don’t have a measuring cup.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Show HN</title><link href="https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/04/29/hn-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Show HN" /><published>2022-04-29T00:36:58-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-29T00:36:58-04:00</updated><id>https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/04/29/hn-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/04/29/hn-post.html"><![CDATA[<p>As seen here: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=31201528</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>Hi HN,

COVID lockdowns made me and my wife cook a lot more at home, and we had a need to streamline our recipe management woes. These were some of the problems we identified:

  - Most recipe websites are what I call "mommy blogs", and the principal problem is that the recipe ingredient list and instructions are buried in a SEO-laden essay that we don't care about. We were sharing links to our favorite recipes, but links don't allow you to skip past the unnecessary essay prefacing the recipe. We knew we wanted a way to have recipes uncompromised by unrelated essays.
  - Popular recipe aggregating websites are run by publishing companies that do not want you, the reader, to contribute your own recipes. This is not true for all of them; Allrecipes.com does allow you to enter recipes but that UI leaves a lot to be desired. We knew we needed a way for us (and you) to write your own recipes.
  - Most recipe websites do not allow you to scale recipe ingredients. We like to cook a lot at once, and we don't like to keep track of a 2x, or 3x multiplier in our heads while cooking. We knew we wanted a simple way of scaling ingredients.
  - Most recipe websites do not contain adequate nutrition information about their recipes. When they do, they don't show their math, or their sources. We knew we needed an automatic nutrition calculation for recipes based on ingredients and their quantities.

After a few months of nights and weekends, we are ready to share https://letscooktime.com . We solved all of the primary problems listed above, and more! Our features:

  - Recipe creation: You can write your own recipes on CookTime, and share them with the world. 
  - Ingredient highlights: CookTime will highlight ingredients by name in the recipe's instructions, and if you click or tap on them we will show you the quantity needed. This becomes important when you're following a recipe on a phone because it saves you having to scroll back and forth between ingredient manifests and recipe text. 
  - Recipe components: Most recipes are simple enough to not need this feature, but some recipes are complex in a specific way: the same ingredient is used multiple times in different quantities. This seems to be more common in baking recipes; you may use flour or sugar in different components (like a pie crust vs. a filling) at different times with different quantities. 
  - Automatic nutrition calculation: CookTime contains the full dataset of the USDA Legacy Standard Reference nutrition dataset and part of the Branded Foods dataset. We associate ingredients with their corresponding entry in the dataset, scale based on mass, volume, or quantity, and then use that to compute nutrition facts for a recipe. Some ingredients may not have an association, and in that case we can fix that by editing the database directly (work in progress to improve this :)) 
  - Grocery lists: You can add recipes to a grocery list, and if they have overlapping ingredients CookTime will simply add them up and show you a unified view of the groceries you need to buy.
  - Scaling recipes: Nothing much to say here, it works.
  - Tagging: The tagging system internally is generic enough, but we are currently limiting the set of allowed tags. Needless to say, you can tag recipes.
  - No blogging, just recipes! No bullshit essay to scroll through.

We think the closest thing to CookTime is https://www.paprikaapp.com. Paprika is a paid native app, CookTime is a free mobile-ready website you can try _today_. I do not believe that recipe management really requires the performance, development cost, and App Store cost of a native app. 

Without a CookTime account, you can:

  - Browse recipes 
  - Read their nutrition facts
  - Scale ingredients temporarily
  - Share links to recipes

With a CookTime account, you can:

  - Add your own recipes
  - Add recipes to your personal groceries list

Let me know what you think! Would you use it? What are you currently using to track your recipes? What missing feature is stopping you from using CookTime?
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As seen here: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=31201528]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recipe Ownership</title><link href="https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/04/28/recipe-ownership.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recipe Ownership" /><published>2022-04-28T15:36:58-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-28T15:36:58-04:00</updated><id>https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/04/28/recipe-ownership</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/04/28/recipe-ownership.html"><![CDATA[<p>Now that CookTime supports user accounts, it is possible to assign ownership of recipes to specific users.
As of today, recipes will now have an “owner”, and only the owner will be allowed to edit or delete the recipe.
All existing recipes will be assigned to either Camila or Gustavo for ownership, depending on who likes the recipe the most.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now that CookTime supports user accounts, it is possible to assign ownership of recipes to specific users. As of today, recipes will now have an “owner”, and only the owner will be allowed to edit or delete the recipe. All existing recipes will be assigned to either Camila or Gustavo for ownership, depending on who likes the recipe the most.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CookTime accounts</title><link href="https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/04/18/accounts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CookTime accounts" /><published>2022-04-18T20:36:58-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-18T20:36:58-04:00</updated><id>https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/04/18/accounts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/04/18/accounts.html"><![CDATA[<p>We have finished implementing accounts on CookTime.
Accounts will allow for some exciting new features like:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Favorite recipes ✅</li>
  <li>Private recipes</li>
  <li>Ratings ✅</li>
  <li>Comments</li>
  <li>Recipe lists</li>
  <li>Personal shopping lists ✅</li>
</ol>

<p>And many more!
To create an account, navigate to the Sign In page and fill in the form.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We have finished implementing accounts on CookTime. Accounts will allow for some exciting new features like: Favorite recipes ✅ Private recipes Ratings ✅ Comments Recipe lists Personal shopping lists ✅]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to CookTime!</title><link href="https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/04/18/welcome-to-cooktime-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to CookTime!" /><published>2022-04-18T19:36:58-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-18T19:36:58-04:00</updated><id>https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/04/18/welcome-to-cooktime-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://letscooktime.com/Blog/2022/04/18/welcome-to-cooktime-blog.html"><![CDATA[<p>We will use this blog to write about new features added to CookTime!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We will use this blog to write about new features added to CookTime!]]></summary></entry></feed>